Finding Aid for the Donald Davie2 Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Donald Davie2 Papers
1942-1995
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0102
3.26 Linear Feet 8 Hollinger boxes
Scope and Contents
The papers of author, educator, poet, and critic Donald Davie consist of his writings, published and unpublished, printed and in draft form, both manuscripts and typescripts, literary correspondence, personal and biographical data, materials pertaining to his academic career and other professional activities, works of his associates and colleagues, and writings by other twentieth century poets and authors, some of them Davie’s students. The earliest materials are letters Davie wrote as a young man in the Royal Navy in 1942 and the latest are his obituaries written in 1995. The papers consist of these series: I. Writings II. Correspondence (Literary) III. Personal and Biographical Data IV. Academic Career V. Professional Activities VI. Associates and Colleagues VII. Writings by Others The series Writing includes some printed material, but the majority of this series is in manuscript or typescript. An oversized box contains a handcrafted book of poems by Davie and photographs by his wife, Doreen Davie. These materials date from 1947 until 1988. The subseries are: Poems and Translations Essays and Articles Reviews Lectures (Not class lectures) Book Manuscripts Bibliographies Tables of Contents and Book Plans Notebook The series Correspondence (Literary) consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence. It is arranged alphabetically by the correspondent’s last name. These letters range in date from 1958 until 1989. The series Personal and Biographical Data consists of a handwritten account of his wartime experiences in Russia, personal correspondence of that era, and his obituaries. These materials range in date from 1942 until 1995. The subseries are: Autobiography Personal Correspondence Obituaries The series Academic Career consists of press clippings, materials relating to his university career in Britain, and his lecture notes, arranged by subject, in typescript and manuscript. Most of the lecture notes appear to date from his seven years at Trinity College Dublin. The items in this series range in date from 1951 until 1988. The subseries are: Clippings Correspondence and Memoranda Lecture notes The series Professional Activities consists of audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes recorded by Davie and materials from the journal PNR during the time Davie was editor. The materials date from 1972 until? The subseries are: Recorded Readings PNR Materials---Editing The series Associates and Colleagues consists of manuscripts and printed materials by Howard Warshaw and Peter Whigham, both colleagues of Davie at Stanford, whose works he supported and promoted. The materials in this series date from 1969 until 1983. The subseries are: Warshaw, Howard Whigham, Peter The series Writings by Others consists of critiques of Davie’s work and influence, proof copies Davie received to review, poetry of Davie’s students, and off-prints and books written by twentieth century poets and academics on the subject of poets and poetry. These materials range in date from 1922 until 1987. The materials dated in the 1920s are Xeroxed copies of material by Ivor Gurney (d. 1937), but they were copied for Davie in 1988. The subseries are: About Donald Davie Proof Copies Received for Review Student Poetry Twentieth Century Poets and Authors
- Writings, 1947-1988
  - Poems and Translations
    - Test item (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Across the Bay (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - After An Accident (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - After the Accident (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - After the Match (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Against Confidences (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agave in the West (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - An Acquaintance (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Anecdote of Transitions (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Asking for It (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - At the First Turning (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - At Sea (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Auto Wrecking (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barnsley Cricket Club (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barnsley & District (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A Battlefield (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Bawdy Loves of Injuste (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Between Dead and Alive (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bolyai, the Geometer (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Boy Scouts Sing for William Yeats (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Child's Play (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A Christening (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Christmas Eve Carol (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Coastal Redwoods, California (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Coming to Maricopa (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Confession of Jovan Babic (1915), also known as Testament of Jovan Babic (1915) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Criccieth (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Cypress Avenue (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Déraciné (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dublin Boy (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Duplicity in Prayer (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ebenezer's Son (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The English and the Russian Poet (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Expecting Venice (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Explanation (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Farmer's Wife: at Foston's Ash (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Feeders (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - First Love (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Flatterers (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - For the Duchess of Wellington (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - From the Kaibab Forest (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gangsters Talk (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Gardens of Savoy (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Grey Squirrel (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hidden Persuaders (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Hill Field (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - His Fair Compatriot (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Homage to John L. Stephens (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Horde (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hornet (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Housekeeping (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Humanly Speaking (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hyphens (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - In California (2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - In Chopin's Garden (2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - In Course of Custom's Lapse (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - In the Watermeadows (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Indian Summer (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Intrusions (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - In the Forests of Lithuania (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Homestead (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Castle (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Gathering of Mushrooms (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Drawing Room (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Year 1812 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - John Maydew, or the Allotment (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Knowing and Showing -see alternate title Thanks (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Landfall and Funeral (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Life Encompassed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A Lily at Noon (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Love and the Times (2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Low Lands (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Marriage (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A Measured Tread (5) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A Meeting of Cultures (3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Metals (2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Middle Age: Phyader -see alternate title Rhyader (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mister Parkman Among the Indians (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Navy Day at Devonport (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - New Dawn (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - New York in August (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Nineteen-Sixties in Wales (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Nine-year old, Touring for Di. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - North and South (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ode to the Soul of Friendship (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Of George and Mary Oppen (2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Of the Will (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - On Generous Lines (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - On Not Deserving (3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Orford (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - On Receiving a Heavy Pocketknife (2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Orion (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Parochial (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Past and Present (2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Pegasus (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Perspectives (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Porec (2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Portland (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Prolific Spell -also contains Piazza Tartini (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Prompters (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Red Rock of Utah (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Red Mills (5) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Reminded of Bougainville (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Resolutions (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Return to Hinton (2) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Rhyader (3) -see alternate title Middle Age (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Right Wing Sympathies (3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The River (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Salute to Pushkin (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - San Bernadino (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Savannah, For Alexander Heard (2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sculptures in Hungary (3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - A Sequence for Francis Parkman (2) plus worksheets (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Shambles Street after Seven Years (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Soliloquy of the Minister for Culture (2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Smoking Habits (2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Stone Guest (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Storm Passing Over (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Stratford on Avon (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Swineherd (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Telephone Call from the Palace of Art (2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Thanks (2) -alternate title Knowing and Showing (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - To the Age of Bronze (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - To Scott Fitzgerald (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tolstoy at Christmas (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Through Bifocals (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The University of the South (4) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Untitled (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Vezelay (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Viper Man (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Virtual Space (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Visiting Day at the General Hospital (2) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Vindication of Jovan Babic (1915) -alternate title Confession of Jovan Babic (1915) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - A Voice from the Garden: for D. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Vying (2) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Want in Summer (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Where Depths Are Surface (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wide France (3) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Windfall (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - A Winter Landscape Near Ely (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - The Wordsworthian (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Yorkshire Antiquarians (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Zelazowa Wola (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Translations
      - Akhmatova, Anna "Boris Pasternak" (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Illyes, Gyula "Horror" (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Mandelstam "on Dante, Voronezh. 1937" (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Pasternak, Boris -from "Dr. Zhivago" (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - August (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Autumn (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - The Bad Days (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - The Breach (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Christmas Star (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Daybreak (3) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Earth (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Explanation (2) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Fairy Story (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Foul Ways in Springtime (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hamlet (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - In Passion Week (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Pasternak, Boris -from "Dr. Zhivago" (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Magdalene I (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Magdalene II (3) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - March (2) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - The Miracle (2) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Rendezvous (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Summer in the City (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Wedding (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Wind (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - White Night (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Pasternak, Boris -The Break (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Pasternak, Boris -Death of a Poet (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Pasternak, Boris -Grass and Stone (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Pasternak, Boris -Soul (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Vyazemsky, P. A. -Stanzas to Davydov (1854) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Essays and Articles
    - Academicism and Jonathan Swift (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Adrian Stokes and Pound's "Cantos" (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Augustans Old and New (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Austin Clark (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Baroque in the Hymn-book (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berkeley and the Style of Dialogue (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berkeley's Style in "Siris" (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Breath-Pause and the Caesura in 16th century Verse (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Can Literary History be Permitted? (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Conservatism of N. S. Leskov (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Deserted Village: Poem as Virtual History (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Disaffection of the Dissenters under George III (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Dostoievsky and the Dandy (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Dramatic Poetry: Dryden's Conversation-Piece (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - The Dry Salvages (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - The Earnest and the Smart Provincialism in Letters (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Elitism, and So On (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - From the Marches of Christendom: Mandelstam and Milosz (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Hardy's Poems of 1912-1913 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Is there a London Literary Racket? (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ivor Gurney (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Kaethchen of Heilbronn by Heinrich von Kleist (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Landscape as Poetic Focus (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Niedecker and Historicity (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Notes to Zhivago's "The Wedding" (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Notes on "White Night" (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Parochial Reflectinos of a Man of Letters (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Poems of Prince Vyazemsky (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Port in the Imaginary Museum (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The Poet Thomas Hardy (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Poetry and Philosophy. For Vicki Hearne. Also "Three Allusions to Issac Watts" and "Three Allusions to George Berkeley" (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Poetry and Politics in Tomlinson (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Poetry of Coleridge (2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Poetry, or Poems? (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Postmodernism and Allen Curnow (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Postmodernism, Craft, and the Market for Poetry (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Rob Roy: An Introduction (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Scientist; Philosopher; Poet (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Sir Herbert Read's Romanticism (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - A Son of Ezra (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Stories of Ivan Bunin (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Strength and Ease of Terms of Seventeenth Century Criticism (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - To See and Not to See You by Rafael Alberti translated by Lloyd Mallan (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Trying to Explain (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Verse Translation (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Warshaw, Howard -preface by Davie for Warshaw's "Drawings on Drawing" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reviews
    - Akhmatova, Anna. Translation by Judith Hemschemeyer. The Complete Poems of Anna Akhmatova. (2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bunting, Basil. Richard Caddel, ed. Uncollected Poems (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Forde, Victoria. The Poetry of Basil Bunting (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Browning, Robert. John Woolford and Daniel Kaelin, eds. The Poems of Browing (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Clare, John. H. Haughton, A. Phillips, and G. Summerfield, eds. John Clare in Context (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Crawford, Robert. Devolving English Literature. Also Dunn, Douglas, ed. Faber Books of Twentieth Century Scottish Poetry (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dale, Peter. Mortal Fire. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Davis, Paul. Dryden's Imaginary Commonwealth (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Eastwood, John. David Middleton, ed. Mind and Blood: The Collected Poems of John Finlay. And Hermetic Light, Essays on the Gnostic Spirit in Modern Literature and Thought (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Fowler, Alastair, ed. The New Oxford Book of Seventeenth Century Verse. Also Hill, Geoffrey. The Enemy's Country (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gross, John, ed. The Oxford Book of Essays (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gurney, Ivor. R. K. R. Thornton, ed. Ivor Gurney: Collected Letters. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Lowell, Robert. Collected Prose. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - McGann, Jerome J. Black Riders: The Visible Language of Modernism (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - McGann, Jerome J., ed. The New Oxford Book of Romantic Period Verse. (2) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Murray, Les. The Paperback Tree. Selected Prose. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Nabakov, Vladimir. The Gift. Review printed on unidentified newspaper, plus draft and notes for the review (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Paz, Octavio. Helen Lane, trans. The Other Voice. Poetry and the Fin-de-siecle. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Robinson, Peter. In The Circumstances: About Poems and Poets (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Rosenberg, David and Harold Bloom, trans. The Book of J. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Tomlinson, Charles. Poetry and Metamorphosis. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Trickett, Rachel. Pope and the Man of Ross. The Honest Muse: A Study in Augustin Verse. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Weissbort, Daniel, ed. The Poetry of Survival. Post-War Poets of Central and Eastern Europe. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Ziolkowski, Theodore. Virgil and the Moderns (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lectures (not class lectures)
    - Aesthetic Value –Judgements in Literary Criticism or What Do We Mean When We Say “This is a Good Poem?” Address to the Irish Philosophical Club., undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - American Poetry Through British Eyes. Addressed to the Friends of the Joint University Libraries of Vanderbilt University., undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - D. H. Lawrence, Englishman., undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Marianne Moore. A paper for the Cambridge English Club. Undated. Also a fragment of a critique of review in “Scrutiny” Vol. IV., no. 1, June 1935. pp. 87-90 of Selected Poems of Marianne Moore. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Poet in the Imaginary Museum. Introduction to the 2nd of two talks., undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - The Poet Keats. Delivered to Perse School Literary Society, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Poetic License and Civil Freedoms –The Poets Role in a time of Social Ferment. Address to the Wilshire Boulevard Temple, Los Angeles, California, 1970 February (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - The Russian Novel –draft of a paper for the Shirley Society, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Sacred Poetry of Jack Clemo. Endowed lecture to the University of Surrey (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Tolstoy. An Hours Talk, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - A Tribute to Allen Tate. Delivered at Vanderbilt University –an introduction to an address by Robert Pinsky., undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Values and Heritage. Delivered at Tate Gallery, London, England. Also a photocopy of an article in The Independent announcing the conference “Art and Value” with handwritten comments by Davie., 1993 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Henry Vaughn and the 17th Century Psalmists, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - William Butler Yeats and the Savile Club, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Book Manuscripts
    - Foreword to a Penguin reprint of Purity of Diction in English Verse (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Cover by Donald Davie for Juvenilia in Verse. No Contents, 1988 March (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bibliographies
    - English Translations of Russian Fiction in Book Form (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Essays and Articles on Russian Writers of Fiction Appearing in English Periodicals Between 1882-1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Reading List for Lectures on 18th century Poetry (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Tolstoy: Bibliography of Translations into English (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Works in English Upon Russian Fiction I. General Works (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Works in English Upon Russian Fiction II. Specific Authors (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tables of Contents and Book Plans
    - Auburn, or the Civilization of North America (Box 3, Folder 4)
      General
      The book never went beyond the planning stage.
    - Current Poetry of the American West (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Plan for Events and Wisdoms. Published London, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Poems (2), 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notebook
    - Notebook of handwritten poems, essays, travel notes, dated from 1957 Nov. 26 to 1959 March (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence (Literary), 1958-1989
  - From D.D. to Mrs. Farmiloe, 1970 March 14 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Mark Brown, 1988 April 27 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Jim Chandler, 1981 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Mark Ferrer (stepson of Howard Warshaw), 1978 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Reginald Gibbons, 1980 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Donald Greene, 1977 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Elizabeth Griffin, 1958 September 17 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Thomas Kabdebo, 1968 December 30 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Dorothy Oberhaus, 1988 January 11 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Greg Miller, 1983 August 18 and 27 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From John Pikoulis, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Paul Ramcey, 1979 October 21 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Janet Adam Smith, 1965 April 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From Stephen Spender, 1989 January 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From John Wain, 1961 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - From George (colleague at Stanford), 1988 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Personal and Biographical Data, 1942-1995
  - Autobiography
    - Remembering Russia. A Personal Record (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence
    - Donald Davie to Rene Haigh (6) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Donald Davie to Dorothy Loomis (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Obituaries
    - Independent, 1995 September 20 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Times (London), 1995 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The New York Times, 1995 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Vanderbilt Register, 1995 October 2-8 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Academic Career, 1951-1988
  - Clippings
    - “Separate Spheres” The Times Literary Supplement, 1967 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Untitled. The Times Literary Supplement, 1967 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “International Week At Vandy” The Tennessean, 1986 March 16 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - International Week Literary Symposium, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - “Culture and Its Rating at Present Time”, Matthew Arnold Centennial Conference, Liverpool University 18-21 July 1988 –Announces Donald Davie’s lecture “Matthew Arnold and the Decline of English Romanticism”, 1988 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda
    - Private and Confidential Memo from Davie to the Vice-Chancellor of Essex University. Titled A Narrative of Certain Events. 28 May to 4 May 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Memoranda of what appears to be a critique perhaps two different recordings of Shakespeare’s sonnets (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes
    - Arguments for a Break in Elizabethan Verse about 1590 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Auden. Lecture (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Jane Austen (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Blake (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Charlotte Bronte (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bunyan -Pilgrim's Progress I. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bunyan II. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Burns (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Byron -Lecture I. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Byron -Lecture II. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Byron -Lecture III. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Crabbe: The Borough (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Crabbe -Lecture II. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Samuel Daniel (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Sir John Davies (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Deloney (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dryden I. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dryden II. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dryden III. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - George Eliot I. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - George Eliot II. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Elizabethan Novel (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Elizabethan Prose -Fiction (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - English Novel (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - John Gay (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Gay's "Beggar's Opera" (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Robert Greene I. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Robert Greene II. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Fulke Grenville, Lord Brooke (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Growth of the English Language (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - James Joyce (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - John Lyly I. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - John Lyly II. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lyly and Sidney (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Thomas Lodge (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Meredith (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Thomas Nashe (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - George Peele (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Raleigh (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Shakespeare -As you Like It (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Shakespeare -Macbeth I. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Shakespeare -Macbeth II. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Shakespeare -Macbeth III. (Box 3, Folder 18)